Brisbane Family Papers
Brisbane Family Papers
- Arthur Brisbane, 1864-1936
  - Memorabilia
    - Scrapbooks containing clippings, correspondence, and memorabilia
      - [Volume 2] Scrapbook, 1885-1888 (Oversize 1)
      - [Volume 3] [Not owned by SCRC]
      - [Volume 4] Scrapbook, 1893 (Oversize 2)
      - [Volume 5] New York Sun, 1884-85 (Oversize 3)
      - [Volume 6][Not owned by SCRC], undated
      - [Volume 7] New York Sun, 1888-89 (Oversize 4)
      - [Volume 8] Journal Temperence Editorials, 1901-1918 (Oversize 5)
      - [Volume 9] New York Journal, 1898-1900 (Oversize 6)
      - [Volumes 10] Ben Hur, 1904 (Oversize 7)
      - [Volumes 11] Ben Hur, 1904 (Oversize 8)
      - [Volume 12] [Not owned by SCRC], undated
      - [Volume 13] New York Journal, 1906-07 (Oversize 9)
      - [Volume 14][Not owned by SCRC]
      - [Volume 15][Not owned by SCRC]
      - [Volume 16] New York Journal, 1911-1912 (Oversize 10)
      - [Volume 17] New York Journal, 1912-1913 (Oversize 11)
      - [Volume 18] [Not owned by SCRC]
      - [Volume 19] New York Journal, 1913 (Oversize 12)
      - [Volume 20] Clippings, 1912-1917 (Oversize 13)
      - [Volume 21] Sunday Editorials, 1912-1915 (Oversize 14)
      - [Volume 22] New York Journal, 1913-1915 (Oversize 15)
      - [Volume 23] New York Evening Journal, 1914-1915 (Oversize 16)
      - [Volume 24] New York Tribune, 1918-1925 (Oversize 17)
      - [Volume 25] New York Herald Journal, 1915-1916 (Oversize 18)
      - [Volume 26] New York Journal, 1916-17 (Oversize 19)
      - [Volume 27] Washington Times, 1917-1918 (Oversize 20)
      - [Volume 28] Washington Times, 1917-1918 (Oversize 21)
      - [Volume 29] Washington Times, 1918-1919 (Oversize 22)
      - [Volume 30] Wisconsin News, 1918-1920 (Oversize 23)
      - [Volume 31] Miscellaneous, 1915-1916 (Oversize 24)
      - [Volume 32] New York Journal, 1917-1918 (Oversize 25)
      - [Volume 33] Women's Suffrage Editorials, 1900-1920 (Oversize 26)
      - [Volume 34] New York Journal, 1918-1920 (Oversize 27)
      - [Volume 35] New York Journal, 1918-1919 (Oversize 28)
      - [Volume 36] New York Sunday American, 1915-1919 (Oversize 29)
      - [Volume 37] New York Sunday American, 1919-1923 (Oversize 30)
      - [Volume 38] Washington Times, 1919-1920 (Oversize 31)
      - [Volume 39] New York Journal and America, 1920-1921 (Oversize 32)
      - [Volume 40] New York Evening Journal, 1921-1922 (Oversize 33)
      - [Volume 41] New York Journal and American, 1922-1923 (Oversize 34)
      - [Volume 42] New York Sunday American, 1923-1925 (Oversize 35)
      - [Volume 43] Today, 1923-1925 (Oversize 36)
      - [Volume 44] New York Journal and American, 1923-1925 (Oversize 37)
      - [Volume 45] New York Journal and American, 1925-1926 (Oversize 38)
      - [Volume 46] New York Sunday American, 1925-1927 (Oversize 39)
      - [Volume 46a] New York Sunday American, 1926-1928 (Oversize 40)
      - [Volume 46b] New York Sunday American, 1929-1930 (Oversize 41)
      - [Volume 47] New York Journal and American, 1926-1927 (Oversize 42)
      - [Volume 48] New York Journal and American, 1927-1928 (Oversize 43)
      - [Volume 49] New York Journal and American, 1928-1929 (Oversize 44)
      - [Volume 50] New York Journal and American, 1929-1930 (Oversize 45)
      - [Volume 51] Today, 1929 (Oversize 46)
      - [Volume 52] New York Sunday American, 1927-31 (Oversize 47)
      - [Volume 53] New York American and Journal, 1930-31 (Oversize 48)
      - [Volume 54] New York American and Journal, 1931-1932 (Oversize 49)
      - [Volume 55] New York Sunday American, 1931-1935 (Oversize 50)
      - [Volume 56] Miscellaneous, 1926-1932 (Oversize 51)
      - [Volume 57] New York Journal and American, 1932-1936 (Oversize 52)
      - [Volume 58] New York Daily Mirror, 1924-1926 (Oversize 53)
      - [Volume 59] New York American Daily and Sunday, 1935-1936 (Oversize 54)
      - [Volume 60] New York Mirror, 1935-1936 (Oversize 55)
      - [Volume 61] New York Journal and American, 1934-1935 (Oversize 56)
      - [Volume 62] New York Journal and American, 1935-36 (Oversize 57)
      - [Volume 63] New York American Book Reviews, 1933-1936 (Oversize 58)
      - [Volume 64] New York Mirror, 1936 (Oversize 59)
      - [Volume 65] New York Mirror, 1936-1937 (Oversize 60)
      - [Volume 66] Miscellaneous, 1894-1912 (Oversize 61)
      - [Volume 67] [Not owned by SCRC]
      - [Volume 68] Miscellaneous, 1933-1936 (Oversize 62)
      - [Volume 69] Miscellaneous, 1923-1936 (Oversize 63)
    - Transcript, "In Senate" testimony of Thomas F. Grady, May 31, 1911 (Box 11)
    - Washington Chamber of Commerce, "Washington's Tribute to Arthur Brisbane", 1932 (Box 11)
    - Will (Phoebe Brisbane) (Box 11)
    - Wine lists (Box 11)
    - Writings by others
      - Luhan, Mabel Dodge / "Ballad of a Bad Girl" (Box 11)
      - Phillips, Wendell / "Toussaint L'Overture" (Box 11)
    - Miscellany, 2 folders (Box 11)
- Nellie Bly (Elizabeth Cochrane Seaman), 1867-1922
  - Correspondence
    - Bly, Nellie / Brisbane, Arthur, 1907-1914; undated; original restricted; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Bly, Nellie / Brisbane, Arthur, 1907-1914; undated; research copy; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Bly, Nellie / Cochrane, Mary Jane (mother), 1914-1915 (Box 12)
    - Bly, Nellie / Guibert, C. A., 1914 (Box 12)
    - Bly, Nellie / Thursby, Alice Brisbane, undated (Box 12)
    - Bly, Nellie / Jennie, 1899 (Box 12)
    - Bly, Nellie / Miscellaneous (2)
- February 2001 addition
  - Biography interviews and notes, Interviewees and subjects arranged alphabetically A-Z) (Box 12)
    - [General], 1887; 1890-1893,; 1895-1897,; 1900-1901,; 1903-1905,; 1908-1911,; 1913-1914,; 1920-1923,; 1925,; 1927,; 1930-1934; 31 folders (Box 1)
    - 4 Reporters (Box 1)
    - $50,000 (Box 1)
    - A (Box 1)
    - Abbott (Box 1)
    - Age (Box 1)
    - Allaire (Box 1)
    - Annenberg, Moe (Box 1)
    - Art Department (Box 1)
    - Astor, Vincent (Box 1)
    - Athletics (Box 1)
    - Bache, Jules (Box 1)
    - B. Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Bannon, Joe (Box 1)
    - Barrymore, John (Box 1)
    - Baseball (Box 1)
    - Bates, Lena (Box 1)
    - Belmont, August (Box 1)
    - Belmont, Mrs. H.O. (Box 1)
    - Belmont, Mrs. O.H.P (Box 1)
    - Block, Paul (Box 1)
    - Bogart, John D. (Box 1)
    - Brewers (Box 1)
    - Brinkley, Nell (Box 1)
    - Brisbane, Albert (Box 1)
    - Brisbane, Alice (Box 1)
    - Brisbane, Arthur
      - Advertising (Box 1)
      - Advice giving (Box 1)
      - Advice to Hoover (Box 1)
      - Advises Nell (Box 1)
      - Advises Taft not to run (Box 1)
      - Affection for children (Box 1)
      - Art department (Box 1)
      - Athletics (Box 1)
      - Begins to shuffle (Box 1)
      - Card playing (Box 1)
      - Changes in A.B. (Box 1)
      - Characteristics (Box 1)
      - Checks (Box 1)
      - Chicago (Box 1)
      - Cigarette smoking (Box 1)
      - Circulation (Box 1)
      - Complaints (Box 1)
      - Copy blue (Box 1)
      - Couldn't spell (Box 1)
      - Death, 2 Folders (Box 1)
      - Death bed query to doctor (Box 1)
      - Depression (Box 1)
      - Diary (Box 1)
      - Dictaphone (Box 1)
      - Dictation (Box 1)
      - D. Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Elizabeth Times (Box 1)
      - Employer/employee relationship (Box 1)
      - Estate (Box 1)
      - Execution (Box 1)
      - Extravagant living (Box 1)
      - Family, feeling for (Box 1)
      - Fanwood (Box 1)
      - Farming (Box 1)
      - Father complex (Box 1)
      - Fight with Hearst (Box 1)
      - Flying (Box 1)
      - Funeral (Box 1)
      - Fowall (Box 1)
      - French wines (Box 1)
      - Frustration (Box 1)
      - Gambling (Box 1)
      - Genesee Hunt Club (Box 1)
      - Germs (Box 1)
      - Getting John R. Hastings (Box 1)
      - Good Habits (Box 1)
      - Gourmet (Box 1)
      - Health/Illness (Box 1)
      - Horseback riding (Box 1)
      - Hospital records, 1914 (Box 1)
      - Humor (Box 1)
      - Ideas (Box 1)
      - Ideals (Box 2)
      - Income (Box 2)
      - Investments (Box 2)
      - Japan (Box 2)
      - London, 1878 (Box 2)
      - London, 1886-1896; 2 Folders (Box 2)
      - London experiences (Box 2)
      - Macy fund (Box 2)
      - Milwaukee (Box 2)
      - Mirror (Box 2)
      - Money making (Box 2)
      - Montaigne's essays (Box 2)
      - Mouquin's (Box 2)
      - Music (Box 2)
      - Nathan Strauss Backs (Box 2)
      - Noticeable change in A.B. (Box 2)
      - N.R.A (Box 2)
      - Office of A.B. (Box 2)
      - Original manuscript (Box 2)
      - Outline and subject index (Box 2)
      - Pasadena, 1926 (Box 2)
      - Philosophies and theories (Box 2)
      - Pictures (Box 2)
      - Predicts F.D.R's re-election (Box 2)
      - Restaurants (Box 2)
      - Roosevelt confides in him (Box 2)
      - Salaries (Box 2)
      - Save your money (Box 2)
      - Servants (Box 2)
      - Shopping (Box 2)
      - Sicker than 1,000 Cats in Europe (Box 2)
      - Smith, Courtland (Box 2)
      - Speculation (Box 2)
      - Stops vote (Box 2)
      - Sued by August Belmont (Box 2)
      - Suffrage (Box 2)
      - Sullivan, Mitchell (Box 2)
      - Sunday Book Reviews (Box 2)
      - Swinnerton, Jimmy (Box 2)
      - Tax avoidance (Box 2)
      - Tired of work (Box 2)
      - To Europe (Box 2)
      - Today column (Box 2)
      - Today column starts (Box 2)
      - Travel (Box 2)
      - Understood Nell's drawing (Box 2)
      - Vanderbilt called me Jack (Box 2)
      - Wanted simple biography (Box 2)
      - The world (Box 2)
      - Wresting with Courtland Smith (Box 2)
      - Writing and reporting, 2 Folders (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Emily (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Hugo (Brother) (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Hugo (Son) (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Phoebe (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Phoebe did A.B. drive her? (Box 2)
    - Brisbane project (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Sarah (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Seward (Box 2)
    - Brisbane, Sherard, Howard, George (Box 2)
    - Brook Farm (Box 2)
    - Brown, Annie (Box 2)
    - Brown, Heywood (Box 2)
    - Butes, Alfred (Box 2)
    - Cameron, Simon (Box 2)
    - Candid Biography (Box 2)
    - Carlson, Oliver (Box 2)
    - Cary, Emily, 2 Folders (Box 2)
    - Cary, Emily, Seward and children (Box 2)
    - Cary, Walter (Box 2)
    - Cassatt (Box 2)
    - Cavalho-Bus. manager (Box 2)
    - Clubs (Box 2)
    - C-Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Conductor (Box 3)
    - Coolidge (Box 3)
    - Correspondence with family-notes (Box 3)
    - Corsets cut consumption (Box 3)
    - Dana, Charles (Box 3)
    - Davis, Richard (Box 3)
    - Davis, Rob (Box 3)
    - De La Roca, Adele (Box 3)
    - Detroit Times (Box 3)
    - De Wolfe, Elsie (Box 3)
    - D. Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Dobson, Judge (Box 3)
    - Dreiser, Theodore (Box 3)
    - Edison, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Education (Box 3)
    - Edward, Duke of Windsor (Box 3)
    - E-Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Engel, Irving (Box 3)
    - Fairfax (Box 3)
    - Figures on newspaper carbon, 2 Folders (Box 3)
    - Fleischacker, Herbert (Box 3)
    - F-Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Ford, Henry (Box 3)
    - Fourier (Box 3)
    - Fragments, miscellaneous interviews (Box 3)
    - France (Box 3)
    - Frostick William, 2 Folders (Box 3)
    - Gasch, Marie (Box 3)
    - Gibson, Charles Dana (Box 3)
    - Gimbel, Bernard (Box 3)
    - G. Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Gottschalk, Dr. Charles (Box 3)
    - Gould Family (Box 3)
    - Grace, Ashley (Box 3)
    - Grey, David (Box 3)
    - H (Box 3)
    - Hastings, John (Box 3)
    - Hearst campaign for mayor (Box 3)
    - Hearst, Millicent (Box 3)
    - Hempstead (Box 3)
    - Herriman, George (Box 3)
    - Herschfield, Harry (Box 3)
    - Horowitz, Louis (Box 3)
    - Huberth, Martin (Box 3)
    - Inglis, William (Box 3)
    - Journal of Commerce (Box 3)
    - Lessing, Bruno (Rudolph, Block) (Box 3)
    - Lindner, Clarence (Box 3)
    - Mager, Gus (Box 3)
    - McCallister (Box 3)
    - McKay, Windsor (Box 3)
    - McManus, George (Box 3)
    - Mc, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - McCrary (Box 3)
    - McCrary Mrs. Sarah (Box 3)
    - Mitchell, Sullivan (Box 3)
    - Modisette, Robert (Box 3)
    - Mort, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Moquin's (Box 3)
    - Murray, Frank (Box 3)
    - N, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Opper (Box 3)
    - Patterson (Box 3)
    - Phillips (Box 3)
    - P, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Pulitzer, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Pullman (Box 3)
    - Queen Marie (Box 3)
    - Radicalism (Box 3)
    - Radio (Box 3)
    - Religious belief (Box 3)
    - Robinson, Elsie (Box 3)
    - Rockefeller, John C. (Box 3)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin (Box 3)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 3)
    - Russell (Box 3)
    - Russell, C. (Box 3)
    - Sherman, Clarence (Box 3)
    - S, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Speed, Keat (Box 3)
    - Steur, Max (Box 3)
    - Stieglitz, Dr. Leopold (Box 3)
    - Strauss, Isadore (Box 3)
    - Steinhauser, Emile (Box 3)
    - Sun (Box 3)
    - Swinnerton, Jimmy (Box 3)
    - Syndiacte (Box 3)
    - T, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Ulmer, Dolly, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - V, miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Washington Times (Box 3)
    - Wertheim, Sully (Box 3)
    - Willicombe, Col. Joseph (Box 3)
    - Winchell, Walter (Box 3)
    - Young, Art (Box 3)
    - World (Box 3)
    - World characters (Box 3)
    - X, Y, Z miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3A)
  - Biography manuscript by Boyden Sparkes
    - Chapters 1-5 (Box 4)
    - Chapter 2, incomplete (Box 4)
    - Chapter 3, incomplete (Box 4)
    - Chapter 5, incomplete (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous pages (Box 4)
    - Pages 14-102 (Box 4)
    - Section II, incomplete (Box 4)
    - Section II copy, incomplete (Box 4)
  - Business correspondence
    - Articles and editorials (Box 4)
    - Fan mail (Box 4)
    - Brainard, C. (Box 4)
    - Cresap, M. (Box 4)
    - Curtis, Cyrus (Box 4)
    - Durand, Nelson (Box 4)
    - Ellinger, A. (Box 4)
    - Fry, Wilfred (Box 4)
    - Godwin (Box 4)
    - Hastings, J.R. (Box 4)
    - Hearst letters, 1926-1928; undated; 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Hill, Percival (Box 4)
    - Hoyt, Charles (Box 4)
    - Immsen, M.F. (Box 4)
    - Johnson, Alfred (Box 4)
    - Krause (Box 4)
    - Landsburgh, Lester (Box 4)
    - Leonard (Box 4)
    - Loew, Marcus (Box 4)
    - Ludlum, David (Box 4)
    - Meigs, M.C. (Box 4)
    - Messing, A.H. (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 Folders (Box 4)
    - O' Reilly, L.J. (Box 5)
    - Polachek (Box 5)
    - Newspaper feature service (Box 5)
    - Pabst, Gustave (Box 5)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin (Box 5)
    - Scholz, Emil (Box 5)
    - Shaw, Edgar (Box 5)
    - Shotwell, Thomas (Box 5)
    - Stanton, C.S. (Box 5)
    - Tobacco fund (Box 5)
    - United Press (Box 5)
    - Vantassel, C.B. (Box 5)
    - Walker (Box 5)
    - War Savings Campaign (Box 5)
    - Wasey, L.R. (Box 5)
    - White, Florenz (Box 5)
    - Winery (Box 5)
  - Family correspondence
    - From Seward Brisbane, 1935 (Box 5)
    - To Albert Brisbane, 1866 (Box 5)
    - To Alice Brisbane, 1933-1936; 1916 (Box 5)
    - To Emily, Alice and Elinor Brisbane, 1923-1935 (Box 5)
    - To Hugo Brisbane, 1922-1925 (Box 5)
    - To Phoebe Brisbane, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
    - To Sarah Brisbane, 1922-1932 (Box 5)
    - To Sarah and Seward Brisbane, 1922 (Box 5)
    - To Sarah, Seward, Hugo and Emily Brisbane, 1921-1925 (Box 5)
    - To Seward and Hugo Brisbane, 1925 (Box 5)
    - To Elinor Smith, 1929-1934 (Box 5)
    - To Evelyn Smith (Box 5)
    - To friends, miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Newspaper articles and editorials
    - [General], 1884-1940; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Hearst columns, 1941 (Box 6)
    - Ideas, 2 Folders (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 Folders (Box 6)
    - New York American and Journal/New York Evening Journal (Box 6)
  - Sparkes, Boyden
    - Letters and writing (Box 6)
  - Memorabilia
    - Addresses (Box 6)
    - Manuscript, Col. William Seaver's History of Batavia (Box 6)
    - Menus and programs (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - News releases (Box 6)
    - Photographs of Arthur Brisbane
      - Magazines (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Package 1)
    - Photographs
      - Pulitzer and Vanderbilt family members (Box 6)
    - Postcards and prints (Box 6)
    - Writings by others (Box 6)